<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScamGuard</string>
    <string name="app_tagline">Be careful</string>

    <string name="nav_home">Home</string>
    <string name="nav_history">History</string>
    <string name="nav_faq">FAQ</string>
    <string name="nav_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Status -->
    <string name="status_active">ScamGuard is active</string>
    <string name="status_active_desc">The app runs in the background and analyzes incoming SMS for signs of fraud.</string>
    <string name="status_safety_hint">⚠️ Be careful: never share your verification code over the phone. If you suspect anything, hang up and call the BANK, Government Agencies, Police at their official number, or your Relatives.</string>
     <string name="status_partial_overlay">«Display over other apps» permission is not granted — the red warning may not appear over the call screen.</string>

    

    <!-- Onboarding -->
    <string name="onb_setup_title">One-time ScamGuard setup</string>
    <string name="onb_setup_desc">Tap — the system will request several permissions one by one. Choose «Allow» for each. At the end, the «Display over other apps» screen will open — enable the toggle there.</string>
    <string name="onb_overlay_title">Last step: display over other apps</string>
    <string name="onb_overlay_desc">Needed so the red warning appears over the call screen.</string>
    <string name="action_ok">OK, configure</string>
    <string name="action_cancel">Cancel</string>

    <!-- Settings -->
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="settings_section_protection">Monitoring</string>
    <string name="settings_protection_running">🔍 ScamGuard is running in background</string>
    <string name="settings_protection_stopped">⏸ ScamGuard is stopped</string>
    <string name="settings_protection_btn_stop">Stop</string>
    <string name="settings_protection_btn_start">Start</string>
    <string name="settings_section_history">History</string>
    <string name="settings_clear_history">Clear history</string>
    <string name="settings_clear_history_desc">Delete all detection records from this device.</string>
    <string name="settings_clear_history_confirm_title">Clear history?</string>
    <string name="settings_clear_history_confirm_msg">All detection records will be permanently deleted. Continue?</string>
    <string name="settings_history_cleared">History cleared</string>
    <string name="settings_section_documents">Documents</string>
    <string name="settings_section_contact">Contact</string>
    <string name="settings_email_label">Email</string>
    <string name="settings_telegram">Telegram community</string>
    <string name="settings_report_bug">Report a bug</string>
    <string name="settings_section_about">About</string>
    <string name="settings_version">Version:</string>

    <!-- History -->
    <string name="history_title">Alert history</string>
    <string name="history_empty">Nothing yet. No suspicious events detected.</string>

    <!-- Alert (new design) -->
    <string name="alert_title_main">POSSIBLE SCAMMERS</string>
    <string name="alert_warn_no_code">Do NOT share the code by phone!</string>
    <string name="alert_warn_hangup">Hang up and call the bank at the official number on the back of your card.</string>
    <string name="alert_warn_never_ask">Neither the bank, the police, nor government services EVER ask for codes by phone.</string>
    <string name="alert_meta_contact">SMS from:</string>
    <string name="alert_meta_reason">Subject:</string>
    <string name="alert_meta_call_from">Call from number:</string>
    <string name="alert_btn_hangup">HANG UP</string>
    <string name="alert_btn_close">I understand, close notification</string>

    <!-- EULA / age consent -->
    <string name="consent_welcome">Welcome to ScamGuard</string>
    <string name="consent_intro">Before we start — a short agreement.</string>
    <string name="consent_bullet1">✅ Everything runs locally on your device.</string>
    <string name="consent_bullet2">📵 The content of your SMS is not sent anywhere.</string>
    <string name="consent_bullet3">📊 Only one anonymous signal is sent to the server — confirmation of accepting this agreement.</string>
    <string name="consent_bullet4">⚠️ This is an auxiliary tool, not a replacement for your vigilance.</string>
    <string name="consent_docs_title">Documents:</string>
    <string name="consent_link_privacy">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="consent_link_eula">EULA</string>
    <string name="consent_check_age">I am 18 years or older.</string>
    <string name="consent_check_terms">I have read the Privacy Policy and Terms, and I accept them.</string>
    <string name="consent_button">Accept and continue</string>

    <!-- FAQ -->
    <string name="faq_title">Frequently asked questions</string>

    <string name="faq_q1">What does ScamGuard do?</string>
    <string name="faq_a1">ScamGuard recognizes a common phone scam pattern: a call combined with a confirmation code arriving by SMS. When it detects this combination, the app shows a warning — don\'t share the code with anyone, and call back only using the official number. All messages are processed only on your device, nothing is sent anywhere.</string>

    <string name="faq_q2">What should I do if I suspect a scammer?</string>
    <string name="faq_a2">Hang up immediately — don\'t continue the conversation and don\'t share any codes, passwords, or card details. Then call the organization back yourself, using the official number — not the one the caller gave you, but one from the organization\'s website, the back of your card, or the "Call" button in a ScamGuard warning. Never call back a number left by a suspicious caller or received in an SMS.</string>

    <string name="faq_q3">What is the "Call" button in the warning for, and can I trust that number?</string>
    <string name="faq_a3">When the app recognizes an organization (bank, operator, etc.), the warning shows a button with its official number — for example, 1313 for MAIB. These numbers were manually verified against official organization websites, not taken from the suspicious SMS itself. Tapping it opens the dial screen — the call isn\'t placed automatically, you tap "Call" yourself once you\'ve confirmed everything is correct.</string>

    <string name="faq_q4">Why am I not getting any warnings at all?</string>
    <string name="faq_a4">The most common reason is that not all required permissions have been granted. The home screen will show a yellow card, "Set up ScamGuard" or "Last step: display over other apps", as long as at least one permission is missing. Tap it and grant everything the system asks for — especially "Display over other apps": without it, the yellow ring-time banner won\'t appear at all. If that card isn\'t showing and the status is green, protection is set up correctly and the issue is something else (see the next question).</string>

    <string name="faq_q5">Is it true that SMS content is never transmitted anywhere?</string>
    <string name="faq_a5">Yes. All SMS analysis happens locally on your device. The app has no technical way to send message content anywhere — the ScamGuard server does not receive or store SMS. The only network request is an anonymous confirmation of accepting the terms of use on first launch.</string>

    <string name="faq_q6">Why didn\'t a warning appear sometimes?</string>
    <string name="faq_a6">ScamGuard is an auxiliary tool, not a guarantee of protection. A warning appears for a specific combination of signs (code in SMS + call). New scam schemes, unusual code wording, or SMS delivery delays from the carrier may mean the app stays silent. Stay alert regardless — especially if the caller is rushing you and asking for a code.</string>

    <string name="faq_q7">Why does the app need so many permissions?</string>
    <string name="faq_a7">• SMS reception — to analyze incoming messages for signs of fraud (on device, not sent anywhere).\n• Phone state — to know if a call is currently active.\n• Call management — allows the "Hang up" button in the notification to actually end the call.\n• Display over other apps — to show the red warning over the call screen.\n\nEverything runs locally. SMS content is not sent anywhere.</string>
        
    <string name="faq_q8">I found a bug or a translation error — where do I report it?</string>
    <string name="faq_a8">Go to Settings → «Contact» section → «Report a bug» — this opens an email with the app version and device info already filled in, just describe the issue in your own words. If you noticed a translation mistake (in Russian or Romanian) — mention it in the email, this is especially valuable since the app is translated manually. There may also be a Telegram community link there, once it\'s set up — you can message directly there instead.</string>



    
<string name="alert_meta_activity">Activity:</string>

<string name="category_bank">Bank</string>
<string name="category_mfo">Credit organization</string>
<string name="category_telecom">Telecom operator</string>
<string name="category_utility">Utility service</string>
<string name="category_state">Government agency</string>
<string name="category_payment">Payment system</string>
<string name="category_other">Unspecified</string>
<string name="ring_alert_title">⚠️ Possible scammers</string>
<string name="ring_alert_time_ago">%1$d min ago an SMS arrived</string>
<string name="ring_alert_subject_from">%1$s from %2$s</string>
<string name="ring_alert_sender">Sender:</string>
<string name="ring_alert_category">Activity:</string>
<string name="ring_alert_subject">Subject:</string>
<string name="ring_alert_no_share">Do not share the code with anyone!</string>
<string name="ring_alert_btn_hangup">Hang up</string>
<string name="ring_alert_btn_understood">I understand, close</string>

<string name="alert_btn_call_official">Call %1$s</string>
<string name="ring_alert_btn_call_official">Call %1$s</string>
</resources>
